



 

   //Questions array

   let questions = [

    {

         number:1,

         question: "The full stop is also known as___ in American English",

         answer : "Period",

         options : [

                          "Longest pause",

                          "Endpoint",

                          "Period",

                          "Close dot"

                        ]

    

    },

    {

         number:2,

         question: "Which of this sentence is should not have a full stop",

         answer : "Come here! The teacher said.",

         options : [

                          "The door is open.",

                          "Come here! The teacher said.",

                          "Peterâ€™s bag is big",

                          "He asked if I should eat."  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:3,

         question: "Where is the question mark used wrongly",

         answer : "What a day?",

         options : [

                          "Where do you live ?",

                          "You believe her ?",

                          "What a day?",

                          "CanItakeasip?"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:4,

         question: "___ is used for special emphasis",

         answer : "Exclamation mark",

         options : [

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Exclamation mark",

                          "Quotation mark",

                          "Apostrophe"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:5,

         question: "Some uses of the full stop include these except",

         answer : "Marking of salutation",

         options : [

                          "Abbreviations",

                          "Marking of salutation",

                          "Indicating initials",

                          "In numbering"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:6,

         question: "Which of these is not a terminal punctuation",

         answer : "Colon",

         options : [

                          "Colon",

                          "Full stop",

                          "Question mark",

                          "Exclamation"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:7,

         question: "Which of these is not a medial punctuation",

         answer : "Exclamation",

         options : [

                          "Comma",

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Colon",

                          "Exclamation"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:8,

         question: "The most commonly used punctuation mark is",

         answer : "Comma",

         options : [

                          "Comma",

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Colon",

                          "Exclamation"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:9,

         question: "What is the major role of the comma",

         answer : "Separating sentence elements",

         options : [

                          "Introduction of items",

                          "Separating sentence elements",

                          "Joining words or parts of words together",

                          "Addition of emphasis"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:10,

         question: "Which medial punctuation expresses a heavier pause than the comma",

         answer : "Semicolon",

         options : [

                          "Comma",

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Colon",

                          "Exclamation"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:11,

         question: "___ separates extra information from the rest of the sentence",

         answer : "Parentheses",

         options : [

                          "Colon",

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Parentheses",

                          "Quotation mark"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:12,

         question: "___ performs a linking function",

         answer : "Dash",

         options : [

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Dash",

                          "Apostrophe",

                          "Comma"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:13,

         question: "___ indicates contraction",

         answer : "Apostrophe",

         options : [

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Dash",

                          "Apostrophe",

                          "Comma"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:14,

         question: "__ is used to show exact words of a speaker in the direct speech",

         answer : "Quotation mark",

         options : [

                          "Colon",

                          "Semicolon",

                          "Parentheses",

                          "Quotation mark"  

                          ]

    

    }

     ];   